Jun-Quan LIM

Mobile: +65 81238021

Email: junquan.lim@u.nus.edu Skype: live:e3d8872650aa49fe

GitHub: JunQuann

Online Resume: https://junquann.github.io/

Personal Statement

About Me

I am currently a sophomore in National University of Singapore (NUS) School of Computing majoring in Computer Science. On top of pursuing academic excellence, I am actively involved in hostel activities as well. Being the Sports Director of my hostel, I was given the opportunity to serve the community that I have come to know and love. In order to broaden my perspectives, I engaged in activities outside my comfort zone such as dancing, singing and soccer. I believe that these experiences from differing backgrounds will enhance my ability to empathize with more situations.

Work Experiences

From September 2017 till December 2017, I worked in a start-up called SUP. Throughout my internship, I was tasked with projects that puts me out of my comfort zone. First, it was a tasked to maintain a chat bot that was built rapidly with minimal documentation. It was one of my first few exposures to python and the code did not make my time easier. I rapidly enhanced my knowledge on python and Django in order to understand what was happening and eventually re-wrote part of the code to clarify matters. I was then able to extend the web application to several other regions. My next project was to create APIs for transactional emailing and uploading of images into S3 buckets. Once again, I found myself in unchartered territories as formal education thus far was limited to algorithmic programming. Through a series of trial and errors and continuous pestering of my senior software engineer and CTO, I managed to grasp the concept of HTTP data transfer through JSON, integrate Sendgrid API and S3 APIs and update databases through POST requests with authentication key; all these enabled me to successfully create my API services for the application. This coming summer, I'll be working at Kasisto, a conversational AI company directed at financial services, where I will be task to deploy automated testing and create test frameworks for the program. I am excited to see what I can learn from this experience.

Why I can contribute

[Clear Communication: Being the of Sports Director in hall has taught me a great deal about communication. With 30 sports and an entire sports committee under my care, I had to make sure that I could communicate ideas and instructions clearly to prevent any confusion.

[Grit and Passion: Having academic responsibilities and hostel commitments did not stop me from pursuing a parttime internship which I was passionate about. Times got tough, but I dug deep and managed to perform decently on all fronts.

| Versatility: Though I started working in the start-up as a software engineer intern, that did not stop me from going out to the streets with my fellow marketing team to collect some survey results from strangers. I learnt several essential 'start-up skills' such as competitive analysis and product flow.

[Optimism and Growth Mindset: My bubbly character always points me towards the direction of possibilities. Whenever I hit a rock, I will find a way to overcome it. I enjoy the grind and the process where I learn and become better at something, and this has helped me overcome several obstacles in life.

Having worked in a start-up before, I understand the micro-cycles and fast pace nature of its operation. I enjoy the start-up culture where we can sit across the dining table, talking about the endless possibilities that can ensue from our efforts; and I hope that you can give me this opportunity to get excited about your dreams together.



Work Experience

May 2018 - Aug 2018 **KASISTO** Singapore Quality Assurance Engineer Intern Evaluate, Propose and Deploy initial suite of true functional test cases Explore popular testing tools in the market (Postman) Propose test case management approach/tooling Creation of live chat web hook mock and test cases Basic troubleshooting and content management tasks Sep 2017 - Dec 2017 SUP Singapore Software Engineer Intern Maintained a web application chat bot in Django framework Extended chat bot to other regions by deploying additional instances using AWS EC2 Implemented black-box services for the company's application using Sendgrid and Nexmo Made HTTPs post requests with JSON to update databases Implemented image-upload service with AWS S3 buckets and python Engaged in marketing surveys and crafted summary reports Jan 2016 - Jul 2016 **Freelance Tutor** Singapore Taught up to 8 private students and employed at 3 different tuition centres Managed the workload of students and tracked their progress Formulated teaching resources to aid learning of students Sep 2014 - Dec 2015 National Service (SAF) Singapore Instructor In charge of media coverage for activities and the knowledge of all cadets Expedited the transition from traditional pedagogy to a more technological-savvy one by creating a simple web application for educational purposes Appointed as the vice-chairperson for the Anniversary event where I had to coordinate with multiple vendors as well as negotiate for suitable pricing during the planning phase Leadership/Extracurricular Activities Apr 2017 - Apr 2018 Sports Director (External) for Hostel Singapore Oversaw the operation of 30 sports and Sports Management Board (SMB) Restructured SMB by attaching a team manager to each sport in order to provide more support to the teams Actively discussed the overall direction of the hall and implemented policies for improvements Organized Inter-Hall Games (IHG) for 30 sports which had over 900 participants. **Overseas Student Volunteer** Sep 2016 - May 2017 Singapore Collaborated with local villagers to build community hall from scratch Planted 1000 cashew apple plants for villagers Built an incinerator in school for proper disposal of rubbish Educated students on importance of environmental preservations through games

Education

Aug 2016 - Present National University of Singapore Singapore

Bachelor of Computing (Honors) in Computer Science

(Course details in Appendix A)

Jan 2011 - Dec 2012 Victoria Junior College

• Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level

Singapore

• Pursued a science course and attained 4 H2 Distinctions.

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming	Java	Proficient	
	Python	Proficient	
	С	Basic	
	C++	Basic	
	Shell Scripting	Basic	
Web	HTML, CSS	Proficient	
	Bootstrap	Intermediate	
	JavaScript	Intermediate	
	PHP	Intermediate	
Web Framework	Django	Intermediate	
Database	SQL	Intermediate	
	PostgreSQL	Intermediate	
Markup	XML	Basic	
Server Management & Network	Computer Network Programming	Basic	
Operating Systems	Windows	Basic	
	Unix/BSD	Basic	
AWS	EC2	Basic	
	S3	Basic	
	33	basic	
Multimedia	GIMP	Basic	

Language Proficiency

SpokenEnglish – fluent; Mandarin – fluentWrittenEnglish – competent; Chinese – average

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honors) in Computer Science

Cumulative Average Point: 4.50 / 5.00

Year	Level	Course Description	Grades
Aug – Nov 2016	Year 1/Semester 1	Quantitative Reasoning	А
		Discrete Structures	B+
		Calculus for Computing	B+
		Programming Methodology	CS
		Real Estate Investments and Trusts Laws	CS
Jan – May 2017	Year 1/Semester 2	Linear Algebra	А
		IS Innovations in Organization and Society	А
		Computer Organization	A-
		Data Structures and Algorithms, I	CS
		English for Academic Purpose	CS
Jun – Jul 2017	Year 2/Special Term 2	Data Structures and Algorithms, II	A-
Aug – Nov 2017	Year 2/Semester 1	Software Engineering #	А
		Effective Communication for Computing Professionals	A-
		Introduction to Computer Networks	B+
		Design and Analysis of Algorithms	B+
		Asking Questions	CU
Jan – May 2018	Year 2/Semester 2	Introduction to Artificial Intelligence	IP
		Database Systems	IP
		Probability and Statistics	IP
		Understanding Body, Mind and Culture through Sports	IP
		Asking Questions	IP

The **Software Engineering** module focuses on teaching students the fundamentals of software engineering principles. This module is the first exposure into software development in the curriculum. It teaches basics GitHub and workflow management within a team. Students are required to add additional features to an existing codebase. The existing codebase is an address-book. Students are to think through their target audience and their user stories so that the features implemented are well targeted. Each added feature has to come with automated testing to ensure that there is a smooth integration. On top of this, students have to craft user guides and developer guides which are part of the grading. This is to ensure that students understand the importance of a clear set of instructions for either the users or the developers.

Project Portfolio: https://cs2103aug2017-w14-b3.github.io/main/team/JunQuann.html

NUS Grading Scale:

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn